Okay, so in this video we're
going to be talking about
some agile considerations
for developing the schedule.
Now remember, basic difference between
predictive and an agile.
In a predictive life cycle,
the project manager
is the command and
control project manager.
So the project manager is the one that is
going to be developing the schedule.
The project manager is the one that is
planning all the work on the project
manager is the one that is delegating
tasks to team members.
That is not the case when it comes to
Agile.
When it comes to Agile, it's a team that
is responsible.
In the Agile environment, you don't have a
command and control project manager.
You have the servant leader, who is a team
facilitator.
And so it's a team that is responsible for
the leadership.
It is a team that is responsible for the
work that is going to be performed during
the sprint, during the release,
it is a team that is going to be
determining what work needs to be done
when.
So it's a team that's going to be
developing the schedule, right,
if you like, right, when it comes to the
agile environment.
Now, there are two basic approaches.
You have this one here, called the
iterative scheduling with a product
backlog, and this is the one that is more
commonly talked about.
So it's a team that's going to be
determining the work, right?
So at the beginning of a project during
release, the product owner and the team
and the team facilitator, right,
they're going to be creating or collecting
the requirements, collecting the user
stories, if you like, and the product
owner is going to be prioritizing these
user stories.
The prioritized list
of user stories for an
entire release is known
as the product backlog.
And so during this time, during release
planning then.
The team themselves are then going to be
determining how many
sprints are we going to have?
You know, we have this many backlog items,
these, this many user stories.
So how many user stories are we going to
be implementing in each sprint?
Which user stories are going to be
implemented during the different sprints?
How long user stories are going to take?
Or rather, what's a level of effort if
each of these user stories, right?
And so and so forth.
So they're going to be using remember what
is known as rolling wave planning right so
remember what rolling wave planning is
it's planning near-term items in detail
longer term items at a much more higher
level so in this case a near-term item
then are going to be each sprint right
each iteration so you're going to be
planning or rather the team is going to be
planning the next iteration in a lot more
detail you know then subsequent iterations
each iteration is first going to be
planned at a very high level, but then as
you're getting to each iteration,
you're going to be planning each iteration
in more and more detail.
So that is what rolling wave planning is.
It is planning near-term items in detail,
longer term at much more higher level.
Now also remember, PMI will use the term
iteration and sprint interchangeably.
So in an agile environment,
you have short-term
iterations, which are known as sprints.
And so this then obviously allows for
changes throughout the release and the
whole idea, the whole principle behind
Agile is obviously it allows for changes,
right?
There's new user stories that are that
have been identified.
They can be added.
Other user stories can be removed or can
be lower priority.
I remember again with the whole principle
behind Agile is that you are delivering,
right?
You are delivering functionality.
delivering business value early and
incrementally.
So every two weeks or four weeks,
depending on the length of the sprint,
the team is going to be
delivering value to the customer,
the customer in this case
being the product owner.
So the team is the one that is going to be
responsible.
The team is responsible for planning the
work that they need to do.
The product owner is not delegating tasks
to the team.
The team facilitator is not delegating
tasks to the team.
The agile team themselves are
determining what work they are
going to be performing when
they're going to be performing.
So that's a little exam tip there as well.
If you're in an agile environment,
if the question is an agile question and
they start talking or give option choices
about the project manager delegating tasks
to the agile team, that's going to be the
wrong option, right?
The project manager does not delegate
tasks, right, to the agile team.
The team facilitator does not delegate
tasks.
The product owner does not delegate task
to the agile team.
The project manager
delegates tasks to a predictive,
or to the project team
in a predictive life cycle.
So always kind of watch out for that when
you're looking at these Agile questions.
Now, so these user stories then are going
to be prioritized.
So again, remember,
the team is responsible for
determining what tasks
need to be done when.
And the whole principle
behind Agile is high
value items are going
to be delivered early.
So they need to be prioritized.
So we've got the prioritized list of user
stories called the product backlog.
But then within each sprint, there's going
to be.
going to be a prioritized list of user
stories within a sprint.
And each of these user stories then are
going to be broken up, further broken
down, further decomposed into individual
tasks.
And of course, I mean the official
definition of a user story is it's a small
piece of functionality that basically adds
value, that provides
value to the customer.
Of course, new user stories
can be added to the backlog at
any time, even within a sprint
as well, even within a sprint.
If it's determined, a new user story has
been identified that is very high priority
even within a sprint, then a new user
story can also be implemented.
You try to avoid that.
That is something that within a sprint,
you're going to try and avoid,
but sometimes it's unavoidable.
And so user stories then are going to be
prioritized, reprioritized.
New user stories are going to be coming in
as far as the release is concerned.
And I remember the reprioritization
then is known as backlog
grooming, right, which we've
covered in a separate slide.
Now, this whole principle behind,
you know, which activities are going to be
performing when and so
and so forth, it only works
really well when we don't
have complex dependencies.
And that's a whole
principle then behind why the
team needs to determine
the level of effort for each.
the work, they're going
to be doing the relative
estimate, so then they can
be breaking down, right?
You can break down, you use the stories
into individual activities, so you can
then determine which work can be performed
when.
Now, it says simple dependencies,
you know, this activity has to be
performed before this activity can be
performed, and, you
know, that's usually okay.
But it's just that if
there's a lot of complexity,
right, then they need to
further break them down.
Their team needs to further refine them.
So there isn't so much complexity.
Now, that's one approach.
Another approach then is something called
on-demand scheduling.
And with on-demand scheduling,
it's basically, it goes a little one step
further in that for
each particular sprint,
the team members are
going to pull the work.
They're going to pull the work themselves,
right, from a queue.
So you have a queue.
So this is all the work that needs to be
done during the sprint and all the work in
this case meaning individual activities
and then team members themselves will
determine or i'm going to do this activity
first right so you've got two three
different team members or five 10
different team members and they're all
determining or I'll do this one I'll do
this one I'll do this one as soon as
they've completed their work then they'll
go look at the queue see what other
activities are are left on the queue and
then they'll choose one right now that
only works well, again, when there are no
complex dependencies.
If one activity is dependent on another
activity, so you've got activity three,
that is dependent on activity
two and activity four being
complete, then that's not
really going to work as well.
So on-demand scheduling, then,
pulling work from a queue can only really
be effective when each activity is
independent of one another.
Team members can be working
on any activity at any time,
then they don't have these
complex dependencies there.
And it works best when the activities can
be divided into equal amounts,
equal level of effort.
If one activity is three or four times a
level of effort compared to another
activity, then that's not really going to
work as well.
It's going to work best when
you've broken down your activities,
right, into almost, you know,
almost equal level of effort.
So at any time, any team member can just
pull down an activity, work on it, right?
And then as soon as
they finished, they can
pull down another activity and work on it.
If it turns out that one activity is so
big that you need two team members to
work, two or three team members to work on
it, then on demand scheduling is not going
to work as well, which is why it's even
more important for team members again to
break down, break down these activities
into little sub-activity.
And again, or just like any principles of
Agile, is providing
incremental business value.
Now, this is all based on the principles
of Canban and Lean methodologies.
Now, you don't need to know
too much about Canban and
Lean, but they are covered
briefly in another video.
But this whole principle is just based on
Canban and Lean.
And one of the principles
behind Canban and
Lean is leveling out the
work of team members.
It's making sure all resources are
utilized at the optimum level.
In this case, then, with team members,
there's no peaks and valleys.
One of the principles of Agile,
one of the 12 principles of Agile,
remember, is that team members,
the flow of work is going to be constant.
The whole idea is to try and prevent,
you know, team members working over time,
some weeks, and then, you know,
underutilize some weeks, over.
utilised of the weeks.
The whole principle is so that all the
work is smoothed out.
So it's leveling out the work of all the
team members.
So these are the two basic approaches then
for schedule development, schedule
management or schedule development in an
agile environment.